Contact

chadriden391@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/chad-riden-12845a222 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Laravel Django Vue.js

Chad Riden

Language-Flexible Full Stack Developer - PHP, Python, JavaScript Glenmont

Summary

I'm a top-performing, very language-flexible full stack developer with 9+ years of experience in responsive web development using PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, React, Angular, Vue, Tailwind, Node, JavaScript, TypeScript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and the cloud platform at New York's leading IT companies. My work experience includes a wide range of software development, from software architecture, database design to website/web app development. I have worked with the Agile development methodology to build test-driven code both as a developer and as a scrum master and have experience with many software design models & patterns like MVC, Singleton, etc.

Also, I work well with other team members (mentoring and leadership) and always find the opportunity to brainstorm.

I love creative, innovative companies/clients who focus on improving their products, as well as the growth of their employees.

My other interests include golf, gaming, and music.

Experience

Transfuture Web Design Full Stack Software Developer 2018 - 2021 (3 years) New York, NY, United States

 Responsible for creating new features with React, using React Hooks, and the latest ES6 features. Used Redux for state management and optimized state as needed. Worked with the team with Git and Did Code Reviews periodically. Used AWS cloud desktop, for daily jobs, and Brazil Build for Cloud environment.

Techs used: PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, Vue, React, Node, Express, Angular, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and AWS.

APPSTIRR Software Developer 2014 - 2017 (3 years) New York, NY, United States

Design, develop, and maintain the company's external and internal web
applications, including the main website, and document library for platforms,
and performed code reviews and quality assurance on others' work,
communicating issues and fixes clearly and quickly.

Techs used: PHP, Python, Vue, React, Angular, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and AWS.

makeithappen PHP Backend Developer 2012 - 2013 (1 year)

New York, NY, United States

 Troubleshoot and correct any issues with websites, internal databases, and external feeds with minimum downtime and discuss, analyze, and strategized product design with CEO, Product Manager, and offsite engineers to ensure product specifications meet client needs.

Techs used: PHP, Codelgniter, Symfony, Vue, Tailwind, jQuery, Bootstrap, Python, JavaScript, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Prototypical Software Engineer 2011 - 2011 (less than a year) New York, NY, United States

 Involved in the complete Software Development Life Cycle including gathering Requirements, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Testing, and Maintenance. Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the website.

Techs used: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, and Apache.

Education

New York University

Bachelor Of Computer Science, Computer Science · (2006 - 2010)